Guide to the Austrian History Yearbook papers, 1959-1977 UA 015
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Austrian History Yearbook papers
1959-1977
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Unknown
UA 015
6 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
This collection includes manuscripts, related correspondence and notes concerning the publication of the Austrian History Newsletter and Yearbook, consisting primarily of the typescripts for articles.
Scope and Contents
The manuscripts, and related correspondence and notes concerning the publication of the Austrian History Newsletter and Yearbook. The A.H.Newsletter first appeared in 1960 while its managing editor, R. John Rath was at the University of Texas. After 4 issues, it was superceded by the Austrian History Yearbook, published by Rice University, where Rath had come to teach. Rath eventually left Rice University and subsequently took the publication with him.
The collection consists primarily of the typescripts for articles appearing in the Yearbook. In general, the earliest and the final typescripts for each article have been kept. In the case of foreign language articles, the first translation has also been kept. Any correspondence and notes pertaining to the articles have been placed in the article's folder. The collection is arranged according to the table of contents of each Newsletter/Yearbook.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Provenance
Received from John Rath, editor, 1969-1979
Index Terms
Subjects
Authors
Document Types
notes; journals (periodicals); manuscripts (document genre); corrrespondence; typescripts
Places
Austria -- History
Subjects (Persons)
Rath, R. John
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Austrian History Yearbook papers, 1959-1977; 231196
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 1 - Correspondence, 1959-1962; 231402 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 1 - Miscellaneous, 231401 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 2 - Newsletter articles, 231400 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 2 - Correspondence, 1960-1962; 231399 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 2 - Miscellaneous, 231398 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 3 - Newspaper articles, 231397 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 3 - Correspondence, 1961-1963; 231396 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 3 - Miscellaneous, 231395 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 4 - Newsletter articles, 231394 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 3 - Correspondence, 1961-1964; 231393 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Austrian History Newsletter, no. 4 - Miscellaneous, 231392 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - R.J.R. "Obiter Dictum", 231391 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Kohn, Hans. "Reflections on Austrian History", 231390 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Hantsch, Hugo. "Pan-Slavism, Austro-Slavism, Neo-Slavism: The all Slav Congresses and the Nationality Problems of Austria-Hungary", 231389 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Breycha-Vautier, A.C. "More sources on Metterich", 231388 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Rothenberg, Gunther E. "Jelacic, the Croatian Military Border, and the Intervention against Hungary in 1848;" Vucinich, Wayne. "Jelacic and the Frontier in Modern History;" Rothenberg. "Reply to the Comments", 231387 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Wank, Solomon. "Some Reflections on Conrad Von Hotzen-Dorf and His Memoirs Based on Old and New Sources;" Fellner, Fritz. "Comments", 231386 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Kollman, Eric C. "The Austrian Presidency, 1918-1959;" Kann, Robert A. "Comments;" Kollman. "Reply", 231385 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Houston, Douglas W. "Karl Renner and Austria in 1945;" Kollman, Eric C. "Comments", 231384 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Hanak, Peter. "Recent Hungarian Literature on the History of the Austro-Hungarian Monarchy, 1848-1918. A Historical Survey", 231383 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Tapie, Victor L. "Recent French Publications on the Hapsburg Empire and the Succession States (1952-1962)", 231382 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - "News", 231381 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Correspondence, 1963-1965; 231380 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 1 - Miscellaneous, 231379 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Fischer-Galati, Stephen. "The Hapsburg Monarchy and Balkan Revolution", 231378 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Fichtner, Paula Sutter. "An Absence Explained: Archduke Ferdinand of Austria and the Battle of Mohacs;" Fischer-Galati, Stephen. "Comments", 231377 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Barany, George. "The Awakening of Maygar Nationalism Before 1848;" Hitchins, Keith. "Comments;" Barany. "Reply", 231376 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Hayes, Bascom Barry. "Bismarck on Austrian Parliamentarianism, 1867-1890;" Pflanze, Otto. "Comments;" Hayes. "Reply", 231375 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Jenks, William A. "The Later Hapsburg Concept of Statecraft", 231374 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Ableitinger, Alfred. "The Movement toward Parliamentary Government in Austria since 1900: Rudolf Sieghart's Memoir of June 28, 1903", 231373 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Wurthle, Fritz. "On the Trial of the Sarajevo Assassins. Is There an Authentic Text of the Trial Records?", 231372 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Sterne, Margaret. "The Presidents of the United States in the Eyes of Austro-Hungarian Diplomats: 1901-1913", 231371 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Schroeder, Paul W. "American Books on Austria-Hungary;" May, Arthur J. "Comments;" Schroeder. "Reply", 231370 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Koci, Joseph; Koralka, Jiri. "The History of the Hapsburg Monarchy (1526-1918) in Czechoslovak Historiography since 1945", 231369 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Klingenstein, Grete. "The International Congress of Historical Sciences", 231368 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - "News", 231367 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Correspondence, 1962-1966; 231366 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 2 - Miscellaneous, 231365 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Preliminary pages; preface; Jelavich, Charles; Rath, R. John. "The Conference", 231364 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Kann, Robert A. "The Dynasty and the Imperial Idea", 231363 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Jenks, William A. "Economics, Constitutionalism, Administrative and Class Structure;" Ranki, Gyorgy. "Comments", 231362 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Rothenberg, Gunther. "The Hapsburg Army", 231361 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Sugar, Peter F. "The Rise of Nationalism", 231360 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Hoffman, George W. "The Political-Geographic Bases of the Austrian Nationality Problem;" Koralka, Jiri. "Comments", 231359 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Whiteside, Andrew G. "The Germans as an Integrative Force in Imperial Austria: The Dilemma of Dominance", 231358 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Zollner, Erich. "The Germans as an Integrating and Disintegrating Force", 231357 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Barany, George. "Hungary: The Uncompromising Compromise", 231356 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 1 - Hanak, Peter. "Hungary in the Austro-Hungarian Monarchy;" Deak, Istvan. "Comments", 231355 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Table of Contents, 231354 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Vuchinich, Wayne S. "The Serbs in Austria-Hungary, 231353 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Djorddjevic, Dimitrije. "The Serbs as an Integrating and Disintegrating Factor", 231352 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Jelavich, Charles. "The Croatian Problem in the Hapsburg Empire in the Nineteenth Century.", 231351 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Krizman, Bogdan. "The Croatians in the Hapsburg Monarchy in the Nineteenth Century", 231350 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Zwitter, Fran. "The Slovenes and the Hapsburg Family", 231349 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Lederer, Ivo J. "Comments", 231348 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Thomson, S. Harrison. "The Czechs as Integrating and Didintegrating Factors in the Hapsburg Empire", 231347 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Havranek, Jan. "The Development of Czech Nationalism", 231346 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Wandycz, Piotr S. "The Poles in Hapsburg Monarchy", 231345 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Wereszycki, Henry K. "The Poles as an Integrating and Disintegrating Factor", 231344 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Plaschka, Richard. "Comments;" Morley, Charles. "Comments;" Zeman, Z.A.B. "Comments", 231343 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Benes, Vaclav L. "The Slovaks in the Hapsburg Empire: A Struggle for Existence", 231342 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Holotik, Ludovit. "The Slovaks: An Integrating or Didintegrating Force?", 231341 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Rudnytsky, Ivan L. "The Ukranians in Galicia under Austrian Rule", 231340 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Fischer-Galati, Stephen. "The Rumanians and the Hapsburg Monarchy", 231339 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Otetea, Andrei. "The Rumanians and the Disintegration of the Hapsburg Monarchy", 231338 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Campbell, John C. "Comments;" Grew, Raymond. "Comments", 231337 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Greenfield, Kent Roberts. "The Italian Nationality Problem of the Austrian Empire", 231336 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 2 - Grew, Raymond. "Comments", 231335 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Preliminary Pages; Table of contents, 231334 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Kraehe, Enno E. "Foreign Policy and the Nationality Problem in the Hapsburg Monarchy, 1800-1867", 231333 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Wank, Solomon. "Foreign Policy and the Nationality Problem in Austria-Hungary, 1867-1914;" Kertesz, Stephen D. "Comments", 231332 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Engel-Janosi, Friedrich. "The Church and the Nationalities in the Hapsburg Monarchy", 231331 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Turczynski, Emanuel. "The National Movement in the Greek Orthodox Church in the Hapsburg Monarchy;" Petrovich, Michael B. "Comments", 231330 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Goldinger, Walter. "The Nationality Question in Austrian Education;" Rath. "Comments", 231329 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Berend, Ivan T.; Ranki, Gyorgy. "Economic Factors in Nationalism: The Example of Hungary at the Beginning of the Twentieth Century", 231328 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Holborn, Hajo. "The Final Disintegration of the Hapsburg Monarchy", 231327 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Mamatey, Victor S. "Legalizing the Collapse of Austria-Hungary at the Paris Peace Conference;" Fellner, Fritz. "Comments", 231326 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Kohn, Hans. "Was the Collapse Inevitable?", 231325 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Schroeder, Paul W. "The Status of Hapsburg Studies in the United States", 231324 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Fellner, Fritz; Gottas, Friedrich. "Hapsburg Studies in Europe;" Wandruszka, Adam. "Comments", 231323 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Rath. "A Few Random Remarks", 231322 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - Lane, Frederich C. "Kent Roberts Greenfield;" Kann, Robert A. "Arthur J. May;" Rath. "Two Distringuished Pioneer American Scholars", 231321 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3, pt. 3 - "Special Announcements", 231320 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3 - Bloomington Conference material, 231319 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3 - Unpublished/withdrawn material, 231318 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 3 - Miscellaneous, 231317 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Preliminary pages; table of contents, 231316 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Fellner, Fritz. "The Dissolution of the Hapsburg Monarchy and its Significance for the New Order in Central Europe: A Reappraisal", 231315 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Hopwood, Robert F. "The Conflict Between Count Czernin and Emperor Charles in 1918", 231314 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Low, Alfred D. "Austria Between East and West: Budapest and Berlin, 1918-1919", 231313 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Pascu, Stefan. "The National Unity of the Romanians and the Breakup of the Austro-Hungarian Empire", 231312 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Djordjevic, Dimitrije. "Comments;" Molnar, Miklos. "Comments;" Fellner, Fritz. "Reply", 231311 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Bernard, Paul B. "Joseph II and the Jews: The Origins of the Toleration Patent of 1782", 231310 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Haas, Arthur G. "Metternich and the Slaves", 231309 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Wagner, Hans. "Comments;" Bernard, Paul B. "Reply;" Haas, Arthur G. "Reply", 231308 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Schroeder, Paul W. "A Turning Point in Austrian Policy in the Crimean War: The Conference of March, 1854", 231307 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Kaufman, Burton Ira. "Austro-American Relations During the Era of the American Civil War", 231306 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Zerner, Ruth. "Bismarck's Views on the Austro-German Alliance and Future European Wars: A Dispatch of October 26, 1887", 231305 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Gebhard, Louis A., Jr. "Austria-Hungary's Dreadnought Squadron: The Naval Outlay of 1911", 231304 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Jelavich, Barbara. "Comments;" Mullen, Thomas. "Comments;" Schroeder, Paul W. "Reply", 231303 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Suval, Stanley. "The Search for a Fatherland", 231302 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Jordaky, Lajos; Hitchins, Keith. "The History of the Hapsburg Monarchy (1789-1918) in Romanian Historiography since 1945", 231301 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Haag, John; Houston, W. Robert. "Materials for Austrian History in the National Archives Microfilm Series", 231300 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "United States and Canadian Publications on Austrian History", 231299 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "Doctoral Dissertations in the United States and Canada", 231298 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "Present Research Projects in the United States and Canada", 231297 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "Recent Austrian and German Books", 231296 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "Austrian and German Periodical Literature", 231295 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "Austrian Doctoral Dissertations on the History of Austria from 1648 to the Present", 231294 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "A Partial List of British Doctoral Dissertations", 231293 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "A Select List of Recent Romanian Publications", 231292 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "A Select List of Recent Italian Publications", 231291 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "News", 231290 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "In Remebrance", 231289 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - "Special Announcements", 231288 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 4-5 - Correspondence re: withdrawn material; Miscellaneous correspondence, 1966-1969, 231287 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Preliminary pages; table of contents, 231286 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Neck, Rudolph. "The Haus-, Hof- und Staatarschiv: its History, Holdings and Use", 231285 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Goldinger, Walter. "The Allgemeines Verwaltungsarchiv", 231284 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Mikoletzky, Hanns Leo. "The Finanz- Und Hofkammerarchiv", 231283 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Egger, Rainer. "The Kriegsarchiv", 231282 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Mechtler, Paul. "The Verkehrsarchiv;" Forster, Kent. "Comments", 231281 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Burian, Peter. "The State Language Problem in Old Austria (1848-1918);" Shafer, Boyd C. "Comments;" Burian. "Reply", 231280 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Rock, Kenneth W. "Schwarzenburg versus Nicholas I, Round One: The Negotiation of the Hapsburg-Romanov Alliance Against Hungary in 1849", 231279 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Jelavich, Barbara. "Foreign Policy and the National Question in the Hapsburg Empire: A Memorandum of Kalnoky;" Wandruszka, Adam. "Comments;" Rock. "Reply", 231278 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Anderle, Joseph. "Major Contributions of Czechs and Slovaks to Austrian and Hungarian History, 1918-1945", 231277 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Epstein, Fritz T. "The History of Austria in United States and Canadian Dissertations", 231276 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - "United States and Canadian Publications on Austrian History", 231275 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - "Doctoral Dissertations in the United States and Canada;" "Present Research Projects in the United States and Canada", 231274 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - "Recent Austrian and German Books;" "Austrian and German Periodical Literature;" "Austrian Doctoral Dissertations on the History of Austria from 1520 to the Present", 231273 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - "A Select List of Recent Polish Publications;" "A Select List of Recent Italian Publications", 231272 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - "News from Austria;" "News from the German Federal Republic;" "News from Italy", 231271 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - "News from the United States and Canada", 231270 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - "Alphons Lhotsky;" "Oskar Regele;" "Hans Kohn", 231269 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - "Special Announcements", 231268 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 6-7 - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 231267 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Preliminary Pages, etc., 231266 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Rath. "Semicentennials, Centennials, and Decennials", 231265 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Zimmerman, Fritz. "The Role of the Burgenland in the History of the Habsburg Monarchy", 231264 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Berlin, Jon D. "The United States and the Burgenland 1918-1920", 231263 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Stadler, Karl R. "Fifty Troubled Years: The Story of the Burgenland", 231262 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Zimanyi, Vera. "Comments on Fritz Zimmerman's 'The Role of the Burgenland in the History of the Habsburg Monarchy;'" Beller, Bela. "Comments on the articles by Karl R. Stadler and Jon D. Berlin;" Burghardt, Andrew F. "Comments;" Zimmerman, Fritz. "Reply;" Rath. "Comments", 231261 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Edmondson, C. Earl. "Early Heimwehr Aims abd Activities;" Jedlicka, Ludwig. "Comments", 231260 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Roider, Karl A. "The Pragmatic Sanction", 231259 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Blejwas, Stanislaus A. "Recent Polish Historiography of the Period of the Partitions", 231258 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - "United States and Canadian Publications on Austrian History", 231257 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - "Doctoral Dissertations in the United States and Canada;" "Present Research Projects in the United States and Canada", 231256 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - "Recent Austrian and German Books;" "Austrian and German Periodical Literature;" "Austrian Doctoral Dissertations on the History of Austria from 1520 to the Present;" "A Select List of Recent Italian Publications", 231255 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - "News from Austria;" "News from Germany", 231254 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - "News from the United States and Canada", 231253 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 8 - Special Announcements", 231252 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 9-10 - Preliminary Pages, table of contents, etc., 231251 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 9-10 - Swoboda, Wolfram W. "The Changing Views of Marx and Engels about the Nationalities in the Austrian Monarchy, 1845-1855", 231250 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 9-10 - Varga, Istvan. "Comments;" Mommsen, Hans. "Comments;" Jones, David R. "Comments;" Swoboda. "Reply", 231249 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 9-10 - Wessely, Kurt. "The Development of the Hungarian Military Frontier until the Middle of the Eighteenth Century", 231248 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Austrian History Yearbook, v. 9-10 - Rothenberg, Gunther E. "Comments;" Vucinich, Wayne S. "Comments;" Wessely. "Reply", 231247 (Box 5, Folder 16)